# Wageesha Bangamuarachchi

■ wageeshaerangi27@gmail.com

| ●

## Summary \_

I am a first year Ph.D. student who is currently working as a Graduate Researcher at the University of Utah in the research area of Smart Hospital Room Technology. I have experiences on conducting research on intersection of human-computer interaction, ubiquitous computing, mobile sensing, and machine learning for domains such as healthcare and human behavior modeling.

## **Education**

#### **Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science**

UNIVERSITY OF UTAH, UT: KAHLERT SCHOOL OF COMPUTING
• Human-centered Computing Specialization Track

Aug. 2023 - Present

## BSc Engineering (Honors) 1st Class, Computer Science & Engineering

University of Moratuwa, LK

- GPA 3.98/4.2 (Top 10 of the class of 127)
- Dean's List in every semester

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2022

## Research Experience

#### **Graduate Researcher**

University of Utah: Kahlert School of Computing

Aug. 2023 - Present

- Advisor: Prof. Jason Wiese
- Conducting interviews on smart hospital room technology experience.
- Smart Patient Room log data analysis in order to improve the technology to support the hospital stakeholders' needs.

#### **Undergraduate Researcher**

University of Moratuwa, LK

*Mar.* 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Advisors: Prof. Indiká Perera (University of Moratuwa, LK), Lakmal Meegahapola (EPFL, CH) and Prof. Daniel Gatica-Perez (EPFL, CH)
- Research on personalized machine learning models for mood inference using multimodal smartphone sensing data
- Research on eating events detection with smartphone sensing using multimodal smartphone sensing data
- Design and deploy mobile applications and ML models to detect eating events in real-time by collecting realworld data

## **Publications**

Journals (\* - equal contribution)

- W. Bangamuarachchi\*, A. Chamantha\*, L. Meegahapola\*, S. Ruiz-Correa, I. Perera, D. Gatica-Perez; Sensing Eating Events in Context: A Smartphone-Only Approach; IEEE Access, vol. 10, 2022. [Published | Impact Factor: 3.75] ✓
- **W. Bangamuarachchi\***, A. Chamantha\*, L. Meegahapola\*, H. Kim, S. Ruiz-Correa, I. Perera, D. Gatica-Perez; *Inferring Mood-While-Eating with Smartphone Sensing and Community-Based Model Personalization*. [Under review]

### **Technical Skills**

**Languages** Python, Java

Machine LearningScikit-Learn, Pandas, NumpyFrameworksSpring-Boot, AndroidDatabasesOracleDB, MongoDB

Other Model Personalization, Object Oriented Software Development, AWS

1

## **Work Experience**

#### **Software Engineer**

Sysco LABS Technologies (Pvt.) Ltd., LK

*May 2022 - Aug 2023* 

- Implement cloud-based serverless solutions, production deployment, production support and hypercare
- Cloud infrastructure maintenance and Dev-Ops
- POC tasks on data files handling, CI/CD pipeline.

#### **Software Engineering Intern**

Sysco LABS Technologies (Pvt.) Ltd., LK

Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Implement test cases to test SOAP endpoints, implement main functionalities to access database and test automation
- Development of RESTful-API, automate endpoint documentation and test automation of REST endpoints
- Mobile application back-end, front-end development and UI test automation

## **Research Projects**

#### **Smart Hospital Technology**

Advisors: Prof. Jason Wiese

2023

- Analysis of Smart Patient Room log data and find behaviour patterns of the patients to improve automation within the smart hospital room in order to support hospital stakeholders needs.
- Conduct interviews with hospital employees (non-patients) on smart hospital experience.

#### Sensing Eating Events in Context: A Smartphone Only Approach

ADVISORS: L. MEEGAHAPOLA AND PROF. D. GATICA-PEREZ (EPFL, CH), PROF. I. PERARA (UNIVERSITY OF MORATUWA, LK)

202

• Investigated and showed that passive smartphone sensing features such as accelerometer, location, app usage, screen usage, and battery usage could be used to detect eating and non-eating events in real-life situations with an F1 score of 85.2%.

#### Inferring Mood-While-Eating with Smartphone Sensing and Novel Personalization Technique

Advisors : L. Meegahapola and Prof. D. Gatica-Perez (EPFL, CH), Prof. I. Perara (University of Moratuwa, LK)

202.

• Conducted research on inferring mood-while-eating using smartphone sensing and self-reports. Showed that accuracies over 80.7% can be achieved for the three-class mood inference task (positive, neutral, negative) by using a novel community-based model personalization technique.

#### **MSense Mobile Application - Sensing Eating Events in Context**

Advisors: L. Meegahapola (EPFL, CH), Prof. I. Perara (University of Moratuwa, LK)

2022

• Designed, developed, and deployed a mobile application and ML models (General and personalized models) to detect eating events in real-time by using users' behavior and context with the help of sensing features such as accelerometer, location, screen usage, and battery usage. Collected real-world data from 12 participants during the pandemic period and observed the model performance.

#### **MCollect Mobile Application**

ADVISOR: KUTILA GUNASEKERA (UNIVERSITY OF MORATUWA, LK)

202

• Designed and developed an android mobile application to be used as research data collection app with the features such as: customizing the app to suit different project requirements, collecting different types of data, and viewing and downloading data that can be used offline and online.

#### Call Detail Record (CDR) data analyzing library

ADVISOR: L. FERNANDO (LIRNEASIA)

2020

• Designed and developed a python library for CDR data analysis for the call, message, and antenna datasets. Functionalities: Data cleaning, data modeling, and visualization.

## Awards & Honors \_\_\_\_\_

2017-2022	<b>Dean's list - All the semesters</b> , Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Moratuwa, LK
2021	IEEEXtreme 15.0 - Island Rank 18, World Rank 247, Programming competition organized by IEEE, competed
	against 2500+ teams
2021	MoraXtreme 6.0 - Island Rank 15, Programming competition organized by University of Moratuwa, LK, competed
	against 250+ teams
2020	IEEEXtreme 14.0 - Island Rank 26, World Rank 274, Programming competition organized by IEEE, competed
	against 3000+ teams
2020	<b>MoraXtreme 5.0 – Island Rank 14</b> , Programming competition organized by University of Moratuwa, LK, competed
	against 250+ teams
2020	$\textbf{HomeAlone2020 Hackathon - Island Rank 3}, \ 72 \ hours \ Hackathon \ organized \ by \ the \ Students' \ Union \ of \ Faculty \ of \ IT,$
	University of Moratuwa, LK, competed against 450+ teams
2020	<b>Google Hash Code - Island Rank 21</b> , Programming competition organized by Google
2019	<b>Code with WIE competition – Best Team Process Award</b> , Hackathon organized by IEEE Women in Engineering, LK
2019	<b>University of Moratuwa Colors Award</b> , Awarded to appreciate non-academic related outstanding performance of
	the undergraduates of University of Moratuwa, LK
2019	IEEEXtreme 13.0 - Island Rank 27, World Rank 461, Programming competition organized by IEEE, competed
	against 3000+ teams
2019	<b>MoraXtreme 4.0 – Island Rank 14</b> , Programming competition organized by University of Moratuwa, LK, competed
	against 250+ teams
2018-2022	<b>Mahapola Higher Education Scholarship</b> , Ministry of Education, LK. Awarded to top 1% of all undergraduates
2016	GCE Advanced Level – Island Rank 198 out of 30000+ candidates, Physical Science Stream. Department of
	Examinations of the Ministry of Education, LK. Z-Score 2.2617
2013	GCE Ordinary Level - Distinction, Department of Examinations of the Ministry of Education, LK. 470,000+ candidates